The skills repo continues to go
absolutely freaking nuts, cresting 70k
stars just the last couple of days. And
of course, I have continued working on
it, so there is plenty more to look at
in this week's change log. The big news
is that I have added two brand new
skills. The first one being this handoff
skill, which I showed on Twitter and
people went absolutely nuts for. Let's
just read the skill because actually
reading the skill really explains the
skill this time.
The description is we're going to
compact the current conversation into a
handoff document for another agent to
pick up. Write a handoff document
summarizing the current conversation so
a fresh agent can continue the work.
Save it to a path produced by mic temp t
handoff blah blah blah, and read the
file before you write to it. So what's
going on here is we're going to end up
with a temporary file inside our
temporary directory of this name here.
So the idea of this skill is it's
creating some documents which is not
designed to be kept around. It's just a
handoff document between two agents. And
the reason we have read file before you
write to it is because in Claude it will
error if it hasn't read the file before
it attempts to write to it. So it's just
an awkward little bit of Claude code
handholding there.
And then it says suggest the skills to
be used if any by the next session.
That's an important part of what the
handoff document needs to do. It needs
to not only handoff the content of the
context window, it also needs to handoff
the vibe of the context window and the
intent of the context window. So this
means that if you're doing a grilling
session and you handoff to another
agent, then it will suggest that it
continues doing the grilling session.
Another crucial thing here is do not
duplicate content already captured in
other artifacts, reference them by path
or URL instead. And then if the user
passed arguments, treat them as a
description of what the next session
will focus on and tailor the doc
accordingly. Now, why did I create this?
Well, what I found I was basically doing
this manually. So I was saying, "Okay,
we're inside a grilling session, let's
say, and we want to answer a question
that can only be answered really by
working with code. Now, we could just
inside the grilling session, just, you
know, do some prototyping or something,
but I always felt that was pretty
awkward because it meant that the
grilling session, let's say we were on
60k tokens or something, then I would
only have another 40k tokens to
prototype and give feedback and iterate
before I started getting worried about
the context window. What I really wanted
to do is just open up another context
window with all of the context from the
grilling session and just focus on that
prototype. And that's why a handoff
really comes into its own. The way you
use this is you just say, "Okay, Claude
code, just hand me off to another
agent." And it will produce the
document. And then you take the path of
that document and you just pass it into
the new agent. You open up a new
terminal and you've got it working in
there. So, that means then that you can
do your work inside there and you can
even hand back to the previous documents
just by saying, "Here's what we learned
from prototyping. Now go back to
grilling." two main patterns here.
There's fire and forget where you
basically just go, "Okay, I need to work
on something in the middle of another
grilling session." Or you notice a bug
during implementation. Okay, you just
get it to hand off and this new agent
will go and fix the bug. Then, another
set another version of this is kind of
what I call DIY sub-agent, which is kind
of what I've just described where you're
inside a grilling session or a planning
session, you realize you need to alter
some code, you go off to another agent's
context window, and then you hand off
back to the original. So, it's kind of
like you've got a sub-agent, but you are
in control of the sub-agent and the
sub-agent is not hampered in the same
way that sub-agents are. It's got all of
its own context window, it can spawn
sub-agents itself. You get the idea. And
of course, then it can hand off to other
agents if you need to. So, handoff, an
incredibly cool skill, really useful
obviously in engineering, but also
useful outside of engineering to be
honest. That's why it's in the
productivity section up here. The next
one that I'm really excited by is in the
engineering section and it is a
prototype skill. Prototyping is really
critical in uh especially AI engineering
because you essentially need to use
prototypes as research, as spikes, as a
way to essentially flush out design
decisions before committing to them. So,
these are throwaway prototypes. That's
the theory. And what this is really cool
because you think prototype and you
immediately think UI, right? And
obviously, this is really really good
for UI. But UI prototypes are really
good for deciding what should this look
like or what should this feel like, how
should it behave on the page. But
there's many other situations where
prototyping can be really beneficial.
For instance, in business logic, when
you have any kind of stateful logic that
changes over time, for instance, an
entity in a database that needs to
change based on user actions, you can
answer that with a logic prototype. And
the theory here is that you can build a
tiny interactive terminal app that
pushes the state machine through cases
that are harder to reason about on
paper. This has been really really cool
because it just allows you you can
basically say, "Okay, I've got a vague
concept of how this should work. Um
build me a prototype here." And then it
will build the prototype, you can give
feedback on the prototype, it will
update the prototype, and then you can
hand off back to another agent that will
actually build the thing based on your
prototype. So, you should use this when
you have some unknown unknowns that you
can really only figure out by looking at
code. If you have, let's say, a question
that you kind of know the answer to, but
maybe you don't, then you can just go,
"Okay, let's just prototype this." The
UI one is really cool because it
generates several radically different UI
variations. And it also does it actually
in the root where you want it to be. And
what you'll get is a kind of floating
button at the bottom of the page where
you can click left and right and choose
and toggle between the variations. You
can then pick a variation and walk down
the design tree and go, "Okay, I like
this about this variation, maybe this
from that variation. Uh let's take a bit
of A and B and combine it into a new one
and discard the others." So, this is
really, really good for just figuring
out what a UI should look like before
your AFK agent, maybe powered by Sun
Castle, goes and implements it. People
often ask me like, "What's the best way
to make AFK agents really good at front
end?" And the answer is prototyping. You
really do need a human to sit in the
loop with the agent to give it feedback
on what looks good because UI is so
dependent on taste, so dependent on
style in the application, and often the
AI just simply can't see what it's
building. So, you need a human there to
really apply their taste to it. So, that
is Prototype, and it is real, real good,
and I hope you enjoy it. Let's quickly
talk about a couple of bug fixes that
came up during this as well, one of
which is really interesting. I took the
very well-used skill "Grill with Docs"
and I wrapped it in a couple of XML
tags. We can see this in the raw here.
So, in the raw, basically the issue I
was finding is that "Grill with Docs"
was a little bit too eager to implement
sometimes. And I think what was
happening was that this supporting
information here,
basically these XML tags didn't exist.
These XML tags are the new thing. And
what it was doing is that all of this
text down here was kind of being treated
by the LLM as more important than the
actual text up here.
So,
I think of this is kind of like loudness
in your prompts, where you have some
prompts or some parts of prompts
they can often be like competing with
each other in terms of the volume and
the amount of impact that they have on
the final output. And so, what I did was
I wrapped these in XML tags. I said,
"Okay, this bit up here is the what
you're actually doing in this skill, and
the bit down here is then supporting
info." So this shows the LLM that, you
know, this isn't like an official thing.
This tends to work pretty well with
Anthropic models. That's certainly It's
certainly in their documentation. And so
it means that the stuff inside
supporting info is just slightly less
prioritized. And that's important, and
that's had a really good effect,
actually. At least, you know, in terms
of vibes. I'm not doing evals here.
Maybe I should be doing evals on this
particular case. But what I'm seeing is
that people aren't reporting this
anymore since I added these XML tags.
One other bug fix that I added is that
inside to PRD and to issues, I've added
this instruction to apply the ready for
agent triage label, no need for
additional triage. Previously, it was
saying, "Okay, add the needs triage
label," which just didn't make sense to
me because once you've created these
issues with to PRD and to issues, if we
look at the two issues one, then these
aren't ready for agents. That's the
intent of them. Um some people have come
back and said, "Should we make the to
PRD skill like should we mark that as
ready for agents because the agent might
implement it on its own?" And for that,
you really need to just tell your agent,
"No, don't implement PRDs, only
implement actual issues." So that's sort
of something on the PRD side. Anyway, so
that's a bug fix that's gone in on this
version. Now finally, I just wanted to
show you something I'm working on when
it comes to some in progress stuff. So
there are a few Yeah, basically two sets
of skills here that are in progress. The
first one is a tripart skill here, which
is me trying to break down what good
writing looks like with AI and trying to
make that into a repeatable skill. I'm
just using this this morning, and I'm
kind of fiddling with it and playing
with it, and I'm enjoying it. The theory
here is that you start by writing
fragments. These fragments are pieces of
text that you kind of might want to
structure into a final piece. The theory
here is that authors, they will often
keep these long, long journals over
many, many years noticing different
things, um, thinking about their
personal life, thinking about their
outside life, thinking about their
friends, all this stuff. And these
fragments end up working their way into
stories almost verbatim. And the theory
here is that you can use AI for this
because AI can prompt you to come up
with better fragments. So, I tend to
just dictate ideas into this and it
comes up with this little document of
fragments. From there, you can take
those fragments and find your way
through a potential arc by writing
beats. Now, these beats are essentially
just beats through a potential story,
you know. If you imagine a, uh, a story
or an article or a newsletter in my
case,
where you might want to like, okay, you
need to find some path through the many,
many possible paths, then writing beats
allows you to do that because it
basically just gives you three options
for where you want to go next and then
write those beats based on the
fragments. And then finally, there's
this sort of writing shape here which is
a kind of review process where you go
back through, make sure it doesn't sound
too AI-y, make sure it's structured in
the right way, and you do a kind of
final pass over it. So, that is the
theory and I'm really interested to see
how that shapes up. I don't think
they're going to be ready anytime soon.
I really, really need to put some work
into developing those skills, but you're
free to try them if you like. Then, we
have one which I think a lot of people
have anticipated for a while, which is
this review skill, which is a code
review skill.
And I've really been wanting to I've
been dragging my heels on this because
writing a generic code review skill is
really hard. But the theory is that I've
come up with two possible strands to
make it work. These two strands are
essentially comparing it along two axes.
So, either the standards set in the code
base, so does the diff follow the repo's
coding standards, and spec. Does the
diff actually faithfully implement the
original issue or PRD? I found that if
you only focus on standards, then you're
going to miss spec stuff. And if you
only focus on the spec, then you're
going to miss standards stuff. So, the
theory is that the review skill will
kick off two parallel sub-agents which
check it along that. Now, standards is
the trickier one because everyone's
coding standards are different and
people will need different things. So,
I've I think I'm going to need to make a
skill that tries to extract out coding
standards from your repo in order to
give you a fighting chance of kind of
making it the best it can possibly be.
And I think that will be a different
skill itself. So, lots of work happening
in this area. Hope it's exciting.
Finally, we are working on a doc site
here, which is going to have videos of
each individual skill, and it also has a
newsletter here. This is going to be my
main newsletter, and you can always opt
out of the skill stuff, but if you
really enjoy these skill updates, if you
want to follow everything that I'm
doing, then this is the place. Thanks so
much for following along. Thank you so
much for giving me such good feedback
about these skills. It motivates me to
keep working on them, and I really love
just seeing people crack AI finally with
these skills, and also modifying them
for their own uses. So, thanks for
watching, and I'll see you in the next
one.